qatarisbooming.com 2019-12-11

# Privacy Policy | Qatar is Booming

**1\. Introduction and General Terms**

ME Business Wire Ltd. is committed to protecting you and your family’s personal information when you are using ME Business Wire services. We want our services to be safe and enjoyable environments for our audience. This Privacy Policy relates to our use of any personal information you provide to us online, via phone or text, by email, in letters or correspondence.

In order to provide you with the full range of ME Business Wire services, we sometimes need to collect information about you.  
This Privacy Policy explains the following:

  * what information ME Business Wire may collect about you;
  * how ME Business Wire will use information we collect about you;
  * when ME Business Wire may use your details to contact you;

_whether ME Business Wire will disclose your details to anyone else;_

  * your choices regarding the personal information you provide to us;
  * the use of cookies on the qatarisbooming.com website and how you can reject these cookies.

ME Business Wire is committed to safeguarding your personal information. Whenever you provide such information, we are legally obliged to use your information in line with all laws concerning the protection of personal information (these laws are referred to collectively in this Privacy Policy as the “data protection laws”).

ME Business Wire websites contain hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties. These third party websites have their own privacy policies, including cookies, and we urge you to review them. They will govern the use of personal information you submit or is collected by cookies whilst visiting these websites. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk.

**2\. What information will ME Business Wire collect about me?**

When you participate in, access or sign up to any of ME Business Wire’s services, activities or online content, such as newsletters, competitions, live chats, message boards, telephone or text or create an account using the qatarisbooming.com online registration system we may receive personal information about you. This can consist of information such as your name, email address, postal address, telephone or mobile number or date of birth, depending on the activity.

By submitting your details, you enable ME Business Wire (and where applicable its contractors) to provide you with the services, activities or online content you select.

ME Business Wire also uses cookies (see paragraph 9 below for details) and collects IP addresses (an IP address is a number that can uniquely identify a specific computer or other network device on the internet) from visitors.

**3\. How will the ME Business Wire use the information they collect about me?**

ME Business Wire will use your personal information for a number of purposes including the following:

  * to provide our services, activities or online content and to deal with your requests and enquiries;
  * for “service administration purposes”, which means that ME Business Wire may contact you for reasons related to the service, activity or online content you have signed up for, as set out in paragraph 4 below (e.g. to provide you with password reminders or to notify you that a particular service, activity or online content has been suspended for maintenance);
  * to contact you about a submission you have made, including any content you provide.
  * to provide you with information about our services, activities or online content;
  * to personalise the way qatarisbooming.com content is presented to you;
  * to use IP addresses to identify the location of users, to block disruptive use, to establish the number of visits from different countries and to determine whether you are accessing the services from Qatar or not; and

_to analyse and improve the services offered on ME Business Wire websites. to provide you with the most user-friendly navigation experience. ME Business Wire may also use and disclose information in aggregate (so that no individuals are identified) for marketing and strategic development purposes._

Where ME Business Wire proposes using your personal information for any other uses we will ensure that we notify you first. You will also be given the opportunity to withhold or withdraw your consent for the use of your personal information for purposes other than those listed above

**4\. Will I be contacted for marketing purposes?**

ME Business Wire won’t contact you for marketing purposes, or promote new services, activities or online content to you unless you specifically agree to be contacted for these purposes.

**5\. Will ME Business Wire share my personal information with anyone else?**

We will keep your information confidential except where disclosure is required or permitted by law (for example to government bodies and law enforcement agencies) or as described in paragraph 6 below. Generally, we will only use your information within ME Business Wire. However, sometimes ME Business Wire uses third parties to process your information. ME Business Wire requires these third parties to comply strictly with its instructions and ME Business Wire requires that they do not use your personal information for their own business purposes, unless you have explicitly consented to the use of your personal information in this way.

**6\. Offensive or inappropriate content on the qatarisbooming.com website**

If you post or send offensive, inappropriate or objectionable content anywhere on or to ME Business Wire websites or otherwise engage in any disruptive behaviour on ME Business Wire service, ME Business Wire may use your personal information to stop such behaviour.

Where ME Business Wire reasonably believes that you are or may be in breach of any of the laws of Qatar (e.g. because content you have posted may be defamatory), ME Business Wire may use your personal information to inform relevant third parties such as your employer, school email/internet provider or law enforcement agencies about the content and your behaviour.

**7\. What if I am a user aged 16 or under?**

If you are aged 16 or under, please get your parent/guardian’s permission before you provide any personal information to qatarisbooming.com. Users without this consent are not allowed to provide us with personal information.

**8\. How long will ME Business Wire keep my personal information?**

We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant activity. If you cancel your registration as a qatarisbooming.com website member and your account is deleted ME Business Wire cannot use the personal information, although it stays on the system for a period of one year for administration purposes before being deleted automatically.

Where you contribute material to qatarisbooming.com we will generally only keep your content for as long as is reasonably required for the purpose(s) for which it was submitted. For example, we will only keep copies of entries to a photographic competition for the duration of the competition. However other projects are likely to have a longer, or even permanent, duration.

**9\. Cookies Policy – Information ME Business Wire collects from you**

**a. What is a cookie?**  
A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes a unique identifier that is sent to your computer or mobile phone (referred to here as a “device”) browser from a website’s computer and is stored on your device’s hard drive. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser’s preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other websites. Many websites do this whenever a user visits their website in order to track online traffic flows.

On qatarisbooming.com, cookies record information about your online preferences and allow us to tailor the websites to your interests. Users have the opportunity to set their devices to accept all cookies, to notify them when a cookie is issued, or not to receive cookies at any time. The last of these means that certain personalised features cannot then be provided to that user and accordingly they may not be able to take full advantage of all of the website’s features. Each browser is different, so check the “Help” menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.

During the course of any visit to qatarisbooming.com, the pages you see, along with a cookie, are downloaded to your device. Many websites do this, because cookies enable website publishers to do useful things like find out whether the device (and probably its user) has visited the website before. This is done on a repeat visit by checking to see, and finding, the cookie left there on the last visit.

**b. How does qatarisbooming.com use cookies?**  
Information supplied by cookies can help us to analyse the profile of our visitors and help us to provide you with a better user experience. For example, if on a previous visit you went to our sports pages, we might find this out from your cookie and highlight sports information on your second and subsequent visits.  
ME Business Wire also use a number of independent measurement and research companies. They gather information regarding the visitors to qatarisbooming.com on our behalf using cookies, log file data and code which is embedded on our website. ME Business Wire use this type of information to help improve the services it provides to its users. All third parties are strictly required not to use any information for their own business or other purposes (see paragraph 5 above).

**c. Third Party Cookies on qatarisbooming.com pages**  
Please note that during your visits to qatarisbooming.com you may notice some cookies that are not related to ME Business Wire. When you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, YouTube or Flickr, you may be presented with cookies from these websites. ME Business Wire does not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the third party websites for more information about these.

**10\. Changes to qatarisbooming.com Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time so you may wish to check it each time you submit personal information to qatarisbooming.com. If you do not agree to these changes, please do not continue to use qatarisbooming.com. If material changes are made to the Privacy Policy we will notify you by placing a prominent notice on the website.

**11\. Contacting ME Business Wire about this Privacy Policy**

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy please [contact us](mailto:contact@qatarisbooming.com)
